War never ends quietly.
Fury is a war, drama, action film directed by David Ayer.
April, 1945.
As the Allies make their final push in the European Theatre, a battle-hardened army sergeant named
Wardaddy commands a Sherman tank and her five-man crew on a deadly mission behind enemy lines.
Outnumbered and outgunned, and with a rookie soldier thrust into their platoon, Wardaddy and his men
face overwhelming odds in their heroic attempts to strike at the heart of Nazi Germany.
Don 'Wardaddy' Collier, played by Brad Pitt.
Boyd 'Bible' Swan, played by Shia LaBeouf.
Norman Ellison, played by Logan Lerman.
Trini 'Gordo' Garcia, played by Michael Peña.
Grady 'Coon-Ass' Travis, played by Jon Bernthal.
Sergeant Binkowski, played by Jim Parrack.
Fury is a 2014 American epic war film written,
directed, and co-produced by David Ayer.
It stars Brad Pitt with Shia LaBeouf, Logan Lerman, Michael Peña, and Jon Bernthal as members of an American
tank crew fighting in Nazi Germany during the final weeks of the European theater of World War II.
Ayer was influenced by the service of military veterans in his
family and by reading books such as Belton Y.
Cooper's Death Traps, a 1998 memoir that underscores the high casualty rates suffered by
American tank crews in combat against their better-equipped German counterparts.
Production began in England in early September 2013.
Initial filming in Hertfordshire led to the start of principal
photography in Oxfordshire on September 30, 2013.
Filming continued in the city of Oxford and elsewhere
and concluded on November 13, 2013.
Fury was released on October 17, 2014, receiving generally positive
reviews and grossing over $211 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of hero, nazi, ambush, bravery, world war ii.
The tone is dark and emotional.